Gabriel Anderson

andgate.github.io

github.com/andgate linkedin.com/in/andgate in

Objective

Highly skilled developer with 2 years of industry experience and 15 years of independent practice, seeking a frontend developer role where I can apply my ideation, relator, and strategic strengths, alongside my broad range of technical skills, to build awesome software that makes a difference in the world.

Education

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics Graduated Manga Cum Laude Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2019 3.7 GPA

Experience

SMART Technologies

Seattle, WA

Frontend Software Developer

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Designed and developed an Android overlay widget manager, written in Kotlin with an MVVM architecture.
- Decomposed a bloated widget framework into a set of packages as NPM monorepo using Lerna, to enable students to use the framework.
- Built a iOS-style calculator widget in React.
- Worked on a large frontend team for SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Did stuff on a large frontend team for company's main product, SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Projects were built to company standards, with Agile, Clean, and unit-tested modules.
- Attended daily team standups.
- Wrote technical design documentation on Confluence.
- Built and deployed projects using TeamCity, working closely with DevOps team to ensure projects were integrated into a large final product.
- Won company hackathon with teammates, developed interface in Vue and built a prototype zoom clone using WebRTC to assist senior developers.

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Undergraduate Directed Research

Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Under Dr. Arne Leitart, explored theories to develop more a efficient, parameterized approximation algorithm for the (Connected) r-Domination problem for unweighted and undirected graphs.
- New theories were explored on whiteboard and paper exclusively.

Central Washington University

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Teaching Assistant

Ellensburg, WA

- Graded homework assignments for Algorithm Analysis, taught by Dr. Boris Kovalerchuk.
- Graded homework assignments for Introduction to Graph Algorithms, taught by Dr. Arne Leitart.
- Assisted students during computer science lab hours for both classes.

Projects

Alonzo

github.com/andgate/alonzo

• Lambda calculus interpreter and repl written in Haskell.

solid-orbit

github.com/andgate/solid-orbit provide an oribt-is data-layer.

• Published NPM package with solid-js hooks and components that provide an oribt-js data-layer.

Mandelbulb Explorer

github.com/andgate/mandelbulb

- Raytracer with signed-distance field for mandelbulb written in C++ and glsl.
- Uses sfml to provide interactivity.

Skills

- Languages:
 - o Proficient: Javascript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, JSON, Java, Kotlin, C, C++, Haskell
 - o Familiar: C#, Swift, Python, GLSL
- Frameworks: Node, React, Vue, Solid, kotlin-flow, OpenGL
- Methodologies: Scrum, Clean, OOP, FP
- Technologies: Android, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Lerna, Docker, Bash, Emacs, VSCode, NixOS